LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/irenealegre/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/irenealgi GitHub: https://github.com/irenealgi

https://irenealegre.com

### IRENE ALEGRE

Product Designer irenealgi@gmail.com

#### HARD SKILLS

User & Competitive Research
User testing / Guerrilla testing
User flows
Storyboarding
Feature prioritisation
Wireframing and prototyping
Web and mobile design
Sketching
Interface design
Basic HTML & CSS

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Understanding business needs
Problem solving
Project management
Agile methodologies
Marketing metrics and KPIs
Copywriting
Content creation
Social media management
Project leadership
Resourcefulness

#### **SOFTWARE**

## Design

Invision and Marvel Sketch Photoshop

#### **Productivity**

JIRA
Google Suite
Trello
Evernote
Keynote
Salesforce
Mac environment
Asana

Product designer with a special focus on UX, market research and having a deep understanding of business needs and objectives. I bring a holistic approach to product development, taking into account views and ideas from all stakeholders and delivering designs that are functional, easy to use and understand, and pleasant to the eye.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Nov 2018 - May 2019: UX/UI Designer at Unmortgage (Contract)

Unmortgage is a new way to own a home, an alternative to renting, traditional mortgages and shared ownership. During my time at Unmortgage, I have worked on defining and designing an entire internal tool for their operational team. More recently, I have been working on consumer-facing product for people who have become our customers.

## Mar 2018 - Oct 2018: Product Designer at carwow

carwow, is a marketplace for dealers and car buyers that enables them to find and display the best deals respectively. I was part of the Supply team, focusing on the design and development of their back-office product: the dashboard dealers use to manage their workflow, respond to enquiries, assess their performance and make changes to their stock.

### Jun 2015 - Aug 2017: Marketing & Design at Onfido

I began at Onfido as a content creator when the team consisted of only three people, but slowly evolved into more of a Digital Marketing role where I looked after online campaigns, landing page creation and metrics. As it was a startup, I also supported with event organisation, sent newsletters, managed social media, and many other bits and bobs.

#### **PREVIOUS ROLES**

I worked in publishing for two years, both as an intern and as a freelancer, doing editorial and marketing. Check out my LinkedIn for more information on that.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017 – UX Design Immersive at General Assembly 2012 – Masters in Publishing, IDEC Pompeu Fabra 2011 – English Degree, Universitat de Barcelona

#### **INTERESTS**

I love reading and writing, as shown on my long-winded case studies

I also enjoy taking photos, both portraits and candid shots, and learning more about minimalism, productivity and intentional living.